残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝世 窓辺からやがて取り立つ
ほとばしる 熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
NHK
My last assignment, it's red, just like blood.
Commander Fuyutsuki was abducted?
Yes, it happened about two hours ago.
The vice commander was last seen in the 8th district.
That's inside this installation?
What in the hell were you idiots in intelligence doing?
Someone inside this organization must have been involved.
We appreciate your cooperation in this.
Someone who could outwit Section 2.
Oh no, you don't think...
My OG Kaji.
He's the suspected mastermind behind this plot.
So that's why you came for me.
We believe that you can help us.
As your colleagues, we regret the necessity of including the director of operations as a suspect.
But that is the nature of our profession.
And of course, considering my relationship with him, it's a natural precaution.
Your cooperation would be appreciated.
It's been a while.
Are your invitations always so violent, Chairman Keel?
There are a number of matters we need to discuss outside of Commander Akari's hearing.
The nature of your procurement was necessary.
You haven't changed at all.
And how this affects me is inconsequential.
The subject to be addressed has already become an active issue.
Thus, these measures will inevitably please understand our situation.
Oh, now this is surprising.
Not the committee, but Sele itself.
Creating a new god is not on our agenda.
We hope that you will cooperate, Professor Fiyutski.
Professor Fiyutski.
Professor.
Oh, hello, boys.
Hey, why don't you come down and join us for a beer at the Riverwalk?
What?
Again?
Ryoko and the other girls say they'll come if you'll come.
And didn't the dean say you shouldn't be so unsociable?
All right, you guys win.
It's nice to have a chance to have a drink outside for a change.
Yes.
You know, you're a brilliant scientist.
But you don't place enough value in your relationships with others.
I'm sorry, sir.
Somehow I doubt that.
However, there's a young bioengineering student who's just written a very interesting paper.
Her name is Ikari.
Have you heard about her before?
Ikari?
No, sir.
I've told her about your work, and she asked if she could meet you.
She'll be calling you soon, and I'd like you to take her on as a research assistant.
And her name is Ikari.
I'll do it, sir.
I read your paper last night.
There are a few things I have questions about, but it's really, really very intriguing.
Oh, thank you very much, sir.
And your full name is Yui Ikari, right?
Yes, sir.
So, what are your career plans?
Would you like to go into a corporate research or join a school's research facility?
Well, I haven't really thought about it much, and in my case, there may be a third option to be considered.
I'm thinking about getting married and having children.
Of course, that's assuming that I meet the right person.
By incorporating the S2 unit into itself, it has achieved its ultimate form, Evangelion Unit 1.
A living god which we created.
What blasphemy!
The creation of a supreme being is unacceptable.
Man must not create gods.
No one should possess such power.
Can we trust Gendo Ikari?
Gendo Rokabungi?
I've heard the name before.
No, I've never met him.
But he does seem to be at the core of a lot of rumors.
Rather unsavory rumors of that.
What?
I was appointed as his advisor?
Well, I'll come bail him out.
I've been hearing some interesting things about you, Professor.
I've been wanting to meet you for some time.
Well, getting drunk and starting a fight isn't the best introduction.
I didn't have a chance to say anything before they jumped me.
I'm not used to being liked, Professor.
But I'm quite familiar with hatred.
Well, your problems are none of my concern.
And you're exactly the kind of person that I expected Professor Fyutski to be.
My first impression of him was that he was a rogue bull on a short tether.
Back then, there were still seasons in this country.
It was autumn.
Are you serious?
Yes, sir.
I've been dating Gendo Rokabungi.
A lot.
When she told me that, I couldn't hide my shock.
It's rather hard imagining you and him being together.
He's really very nice.
It's just that nobody really knows him quite the way I do.
You ought to try, sir.
In this case, I think that ignorance might be bliss.
Are you upset that I told him to list you as his counselor?
Well, I'll admit that he's interesting, but I just don't like him.
It was generally believed that the real object of Gendo's overtures to Yui was her obvious talent.
That and the support of the secret organization that was arranging funding for her projects.
That organization was called Sele.
In the year 2000, the second impact occurred.
The first year of the 21st century was, what can I say, uh...
It was a time I still find hard to talk about.
This used to be a continent of ice.
The entire thing is gone.
Professor Fiyutsuki!
I don't believe it.
You're alive.
I had heard that you were with the Katsuragi research team when the disaster occurred.
Fortunately, I returned to Japan one day before the incident happened.
Is that so?
Mr. Okabungi, you're a very...
Excuse me, but I've changed my name.
A postcard.
Not a business card.
Ikari?
Gendo Ikari?
My wife has been asking me to send you this for a while now.
She's still quite a fan of yours.
Quite an honor, considering.
So, how is Yui doing?
Why isn't she on this expedition?
Oh, Yui wanted to come as well.
But we have a child to consider now.
There are a lot of ugly rumors about this organization you work for.
Sele, or whatever it's called.
I don't like the way it bullies the committee.
I'm afraid that it's necessary.
An organization can't have too many scruples in this day and age.
It may be true that Second Impact has changed a lot of things.
But if this official investigation team had been composed solely of Sele personnel,
there would have been trouble.
Were the rest of us just invited for political convenience?
I hate the darkness.
All it does is bring back the most horrible memories.
Who is she?
The only survivor of the research team.
Her name is Misato Katsuragi.
Katsuragi?
You mean Dr. Katsuragi's daughter?
Yes, but she hasn't said a word in two years.
How terrible.
She saw hell firsthand.
Her physical wounds could be healed, but repairing the damage to her mind will take time.
Indeed.
The results of our investigation aren't easy to analyze.
This giant of light is but one of many mysteries.
Later, the United Nations would make an official declaration.
The Second Impact had been caused by a massive meteorite strike on Antarctica.
As someone who knew what I knew, those announcements were obvious fabrications.
Zele and a man named Kiel were behind the cover-up.
It became my goal, my obsession to find the real answers, the truth that was being suppressed.
Even if my former student, Yui, was involved as well.
Why did you conceal the existence of the giant?
You knew Second Impact was going to happen, didn't you?
You could talk all you want to about how it was just luck that you returned one day before it occurred.
But how do you explain the fact that you brought back all the expedition's records and findings?
I know for a fact your personal files contain more than we recovered, Ikari.
I'm surprised that these weren't destroyed.
Sloppy housework.
I've checked into your estate as well.
Bringing up a child and educating him is expensive.
But isn't it a bit much for a civil servant?
Very impressive, Professor Fyutski.
Perhaps you should be teaching economics?
I'm going to go public with the real truth about you.
Sail a second impact in the Dead Sea Scrolls.
What you've done is completely inexcusable.
As you wish.
But first, there is something I'd like to show you.
How far down are we going?
Worried, Montresor?
A little bit.
Oh, my God!
We didn't make this.
Someone or something else excavated this cavity, although 89% of it was buried.
Then this was originally a giant sphere?
Yes.
This geofront is what has been consuming the total resources of the human race.
Professor Fyutski!
Dr. Akagi, you're here too?
Yes.
This is the ideal place for advancing our research towards creating the ultimate biocomputer system.
Hmm.
I'm going to name them the Magi.
The Magi?
The three wise men of the East?
Is this what you wanted to show me?
No.
It's over this way.
Ritsuko, I'll be right back.
Huh?
Hmm.
Is this a giant of light?
No.
In Gehern, we refer to the second impact giant as Adam.
But this isn't the one.
Then, what is this?
This is what man has created from Adam.
Ava.
Ava?
The operation to revive Adam is referred to as Project E.
This is Ava Unit Zero, our system prototype.
Prototype?
Prototype of what?
Fyutsuki, will you join us in creating a new genesis for mankind?
Uh, ma'am?
Oh, sorry.
I zoned out.
Let's proceed with Ray's repeat test.
I haven't seen Major Katsuragi today.
Uh, neither have I.
Huh?
Katsuragi?
Yeah, Misaru Katsuragi.
Pleased to meet ya!
Dear Mother,
I have just become acquainted with a girl named Katsuragi.
Most people tend to keep their distance from me once they find out who I am, which forces
me to remember how important your name is around here.
But Misaru is different.
She's very open and honest.
Even with me.
I also understand that she's the only survivor from the original research team.
She used to be mute, but she talks almost constantly now, like she's trying to make up
for lost time.
Dear Ritsuko, I'm underground so much these days that I feel like a mole.
And I'm getting royally sick and tired of living on the boxed lunches they provide here.
That should improve, though.
Up on the surface, they've started construction of Tokyo 3.
Masato hasn't shown up at college for the last few days, and I finally forced her to tell
me why.
Talk about stupid.
She spent the whole week having sex with her new boyfriend.
A whole week!
I think there's another side to her I haven't seen before, and it disturbs me.
Well, she introduced me to him today, and he's handsome all right, but his sloppy grooming
and attitude really bother me.
You've always been a little boy, Shy Ritsuko, dear.
I think it's because you only had a mother and no men in your life.
And I'm afraid that I never reeled you in as often as I should have.
I'm ashamed to admit it, but I've only acted like a mother when it suited my whims.
Which wasn't often.
The Strudel experiment will begin in five minutes.
Why is there a child in here?
That's Commander Akari's son.
Akari, this isn't a daycare center.
This is an important event.
Sorry, Professor.
I'm the one who brought Shinti here.
But, Yui, this is your experiment today.
That's why I brought him.
I want to show him how bright the future will be.
Those words would prove to be Yui's last.
A freak accident wiped her from this existence, just as I had hoped it would.
What a disgusting woman I am.
Ritsuko, after that day, Commander Akari changed completely.
Where have you been all week?
I understand your grief.
But you must know that your life no longer belongs to you alone.
I know.
Fyudski, as of today, we will begin the new project.
I have already made the proposal to Chairman Keele.
You mean it's approved?
Yes.
That which has never been achieved.
The path to becoming one with God.
The Human Instrumentality Project.
Dear Mother, congratulations on the completion of your Magi Theorems.
I have good news, too.
It's been decided that I will officially join Gehearn.
I'll start working on Project E next month.
Dr. Ritsuko Akagi, Technological Development Section.
Here's my ID.
I came to see how the new Command Center installation was coming along, but I got lost.
The Commander and Dr. Akagi will see you in the Command Center.
Are you all right?
Yes.
I have no regrets concerning my work.
You're lying.
You still can't forget about Yui, can you?
But that's acceptable to me.
And this is Gehearn headquarters.
Good morning, Commander.
Did you bring your child today?
Oh, wait.
I could have sworn that you had a son.
Oh, no.
This isn't Shinji.
I've decided to take care of an acquaintance's child.
Her name is Rei Ayanami.
Hello, Rei.
I'm Ritsuko.
She resembles someone.
Yui.
All of the records containing Rei Ayanami have been deleted.
They're all blank.
What's going on?
Magi Caspar.
Magi Balthazar.
Magi Melchior.
The Magi are the three aspects of myself.
Myself as a scientist.
Myself as a mother.
And myself as a woman.
The three aspects that combine to make one whole.
The three faces of mother.
And all that's left to do is to turn the power on.
Mm-hmm.
I'll be leaving early today.
Misato just got back.
Oh, yes.
I'd heard that she just joined Gehörn.
In Germany, if I recall.
Yes.
She's with the third branch.
So, she's having a long-distance relationship.
It didn't work out.
They broke up?
But they always seemed like such a perfect couple.
The interaction of men and women isn't very logical.
You're always so cool and analytical about these things.
Aren't you afraid you'll lose your chance at happiness?
First, I have to find a definition of happiness.
It's been a while since I went out.
Well, have a good one.
See you later.
Did you need me for something, Ray?
I lost my way, Doctor.
Is that so?
Well, do you want to come with me, then?
No, thanks.
But how will you get home all by yourself?
That's not your business, old hag.
Old hag?
I can find my way home by myself, old hag.
You shouldn't call someone an old hag, Ray.
But you are an old hag, aren't you?
I'm getting mad.
Commander Okari will spank you for this, you little...
The commander is the one who calls you that.
He says that old hag is annoying.
That old hag is no use anymore.
Old hag is no use anymore.
The commander is the one who calls you.
He says that old hag is annoying.
That old hag is no use anymore.
Old hag is no use anymore.
You little bitch!
You're replaceable, too!
Did you know that, Ray?
You're just as replaceable as me!
Oh, no!
The instrumentality committee dissolved the Gehearn Research Organization.
In order to execute the project that Gehearn had conceived, a new special organization called Nerve was formed.
All of Gehearn's existing personnel were transferred into Nerve, all except one, the one who had rendered such a remarkable service to the Magi's system, Dr. Akaki.
Is that you?
Yes, it is.
It's been a while, hasn't it?
You know, this action will probably result in your death.
All I want is to get closer to the truth, to have it in my grasp.
Here.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Is it over now?
Yes, it is.
A solution to the problem has been found.
I see.
Where is he?
I wouldn't know that.
Oh, hi.
You're a little late, aren't you?
I'm home.
Oh, hi.
And there's one more thing to trouble you with.
I've been growing flowers.
I'd appreciate it if you could water them for me.
Shinji knows where they are.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Don't hesitate.
Move ahead.
If I can see you again, I will say the words that I could not say eight years ago.
Bye.
This message is recorded at 0C210.
You fool.
You're always such a fool.
God damn it.
All I could do was run.
Run away from Misato.
Why?
There was nothing I could say.
I was just a child.
Bye.
Boy.
Thank you.